<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Science, Physiotherapy and Stats</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Science, Physiotherapy and Stats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jnshsrs&#34;&gt;Jens Hüsers&lt;/a&gt; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SNOMED CT für den interoperablen interdisziplinären elektronischen Informationsaustausch in der Wundversorgung</title>
      <link>/post/snomed-ct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/snomed-ct/</guid>
      <description>Abstract für die Veranstaltung - BfArM im Dialog „Anwenderforum Snomed CT“ am 18. Mai 2021 Eine chronische Wunde ist ein anhaltender Hautdefekt, dessen spontane Abheilung fehlschlägt. Bei der überwiegender Anzahl der 4 Millionen betroffenen Patienten in Deutschland manifestiert sich eine chronische Wunde an der unteren Extremität [1]. Fortwährend hohe und tendenziell steigende Prävalenzen der Grunderkrankungen, zu denen kardiovaskuläre Erkrankungen und der Diabetes Mellitus zählen, manifestieren das Problem “Chronische Wunde” in einer alternden Bevölkerung.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaining in a FHIR Query</title>
      <link>/post/chaining-in-a-fhir-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/chaining-in-a-fhir-query/</guid>
      <description>In digital health products, it is essential to find health information reliably. As health care data is complex, searching for information in health databases, requests should be flexible. The FHIR specification offers multiple mechanisms to ensure reliable and flexible data queries.
Among those mechanisms, one important FHIR-feature is the chaining of the search parameters, which allows combining searches across referenced FHIR-resources.
For example, a patient has several clinical encounters, such as an appointment with the local physician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Prediction for FHIR</title>
      <link>/post/risk-prediction-for-fhir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/risk-prediction-for-fhir/</guid>
      <description>Risk Prediction Based on clinical observations and classifications, clinical risk prediction models support clinicians to detect risk patients in an early stage of an amputation. Those patients may have a high likelihood of developing severe short or long-term complications, such as heart attack or lower limb amputations.
Lower limb amputations are a feared complication with patients with a diabetic foot ulcer (DFU). In a recent effort, I developed a clinical prediction tool that estimates the patient’s risk of a lower-leg amputation, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Logistic Regression Coefficients - Odds Ratios</title>
      <link>/post/interpreting-logistic-regression-coefficients-odds-ratios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/interpreting-logistic-regression-coefficients-odds-ratios/</guid>
      <description>Logistic Regression The Logisitc Regression is a generalized linear model, which models the relationship between a dichotomous dependent outcome variable \(y\) and a set of independent response variables \(X\).
However, to get meaningful predictions on the binary outcome variable, the linear combination of regression coefficients models transformed \(y\) values. The transformations is done via the Logit, which basically is the natural logarithm of the odds, also called Logit: \(log(\frac{p(x)}{1 - p(x)})\), where \(p(x)\) is the probability that \(y=\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload a Resource to a FHIR Server</title>
      <link>/post/upload-a-resource-to-a-fhir-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/upload-a-resource-to-a-fhir-server/</guid>
      <description>Upload a Resource to a FHIR Server In earlier posts I presented FHIR resources by uploading them to FHIR servers. This post will explain how the process of uploading a FHIR resource works with postman. In this context the correct terminology is post a resource rather than uploading since we are dealing with a RESTful API.
In this specific example I will show how to post a ValueSet I created to capture the location of a ulcer according to the &amp;ldquo;National Konsensus zur Dokumentation des Ulcus Cruris&amp;rdquo; which is a German specification of how to document and communicate the presence of foot ulcer (Ulcus Cruris).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiling and Slicing an FHIR Observation Resource</title>
      <link>/post/profiling-and-slicing-an-fhir-observation-resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/profiling-and-slicing-an-fhir-observation-resource/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is about creating FHIR profiles and slicing in particular. So, just before I start I want to introduce with a few bullet points to show from where this post starts.
 Observation is a common entity in clinical care It is an FHIR resource helping to represent and store informations about an observation made in clinic practise The FHIR resource observation is normative amon only few more resources We can use the FHIR resource to represent clinical observations and store them on electronisch systems An observation may be the blood pressure or the size of a wound, to only name two out of many The FHIR specification is a framework of rules how to represent clinical information as listed above We can apply these rules to represent specific use cases e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finalizing a Lasso (glmnet) Model: An Example using Credit Data</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-25-finalizing-glmnet-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-25-finalizing-glmnet-models/</guid>
      <description>Evaluating hyperparameter with Cross Validation In machine learning we develop algorithms to map from predictive variables to an output variable which we wish to predict using unseen data. When building models we can use hyperparameters of the algorithms to increase model performance.
Lasso regression, which puts a penalty on large model coefficients (see James et al. text book “Introduction to Staticial Learning” for more details), is an example of an algorithm using hyperparameters, to control and find the best amount of shrinkage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koeffizienten des Bass-Models</title>
      <link>/post/estimating-the-bass-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/estimating-the-bass-model/</guid>
      <description>Untersuchung von Innovationen Vor dem Hintergrund immer schneller verlaufender Innovationszyklen und der zunehmenden Digitalisierung sind Modelle die versuchen Innovationsmechanismen zu erklären von großem Interesse. Obwohl die Innovationsforschung, die sich mit diesem Thema befasst, heutzutage einen großen Stellenwert einnummt, befassten sich Forscher um 1960 mit der Thematik. Insbesondere Rogers und Bass befassten sich der Erklärung und Modellierung von Innovationen. Bass gelang es als Erster ein mathematisches Model zur Erklärung von Innovationen und der Produktentwicklung zu erstellen, die ursprünglich von Rogers in seiner “Diffusion of Innovation Theory” aufgestellt wurden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marktentwicklung von Innovationen</title>
      <link>/post/marktentwicklung-von-innovationen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/marktentwicklung-von-innovationen/</guid>
      <description>Dazu kann auf Grundlage des Modells zusätzlich geschätzt werden, wie sich die Produktentwicklung am Marktniederschlägt.
Es ist jedoch zu beachten, dass es sich bei diesen Modellen im Wesentlichen um eine Vereinfachung der komplexen Marktrealität handelt. Zudem werden die Prognosen auf Basis der Marktverhältnisse der Vergangenheit getroffen. Verändern sich diese Verhältnisse ist das Modell nicht mehr statthaft, da es diese Veränderungen nicht modellieren kann. Dies ist jedoch ein Problem vieler Vorhersagemodelle und gilt nicht exklusiv für das Bass-Modell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HL7 FHIR Fundamentals - Creating an Observation Resource</title>
      <link>/post/hl7-fhir-fundamentale-create-an-observation-resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hl7-fhir-fundamentale-create-an-observation-resource/</guid>
      <description>In the last post I talked about the central FHIR resource Patient which captures all the information of a patient, such as name, date of birth and so forth. Another important resource it Observation. This resource is used to give details about a specific observation such as blood pressure or heart rate. According to the specification, we use the element code which has the datatype CodeableConcept. We can use Terminologies like LOINC or SNOMED CT to specifiy the observation type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HL7 FHIR Fundamentals - Creating Resources</title>
      <link>/post/hl-fhir-fundamentale-creating-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hl-fhir-fundamentale-creating-resources/</guid>
      <description>FHIR Fundamentals Class On November 1st 2018 I started an online course on the HL7 FHIR Standard. This course is offerd by the HL7 which is an international organization for standardization in healthcare and it is all about the latest standard called Fast Healthcare Interoperablity Resources or short: FHIR.
This standard used RESTful services and json or xml-documents to transfer information.
As the name FHIR suggests this standard is all about resources which are the main building blocks in FHIR to capture information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Cost Function of Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>/post/exploring-the-cost-function-of-logistic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/exploring-the-cost-function-of-logistic-regression/</guid>
      <description>This post is about exploring the cost function and its connection to the logistic regression function.
knitr::opts_chunk$set(echo = TRUE, warning=F, message=FALSE, fig.align=&amp;#39;center&amp;#39;) library(tidyverse) library(plotly) library(latex2exp) I want to get a deeper understanding of the connection between the logistic regresssion and its cost function. Therefore I created a function in R and conducted a grid approximation with this function. The results are presented below.
The logistic regression can be applied to data where the dependent variable is coded binary where the referent class is coded as a 1 and as 0 otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GMDS Tutorium 2018 - Datenvisualisierung in R mit ggplot2</title>
      <link>/post/gmds-tutorium-2018-datenvisualisierung-in-r-mit-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gmds-tutorium-2018-datenvisualisierung-in-r-mit-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>Dieses Dokument enthält die Aufgaben zu meinem Tutorial “Datenvisualisierung in R mit ggplot2” auf der 63. Jahrestagung der GMDS am 6. September 2018 in Osnabrück.
Die Präsentation zum Workshop sind hier zu finden. Das Repository mit den Dateien sind hier zu finden.
  Setup Laden der benötigten R-Pakete für dieses Tutorium.
# laden von ggplot2 library(ggplot2) # Wir können ggplot2 auch mit dem tidyverse Paket laden # In dem Fall werden weitere Pakete des wie z.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GMDS Tutorium 2018 - Der Einstieg in die Programmiersprache R</title>
      <link>/post/r-tutorium-gmds-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-tutorium-gmds-2018/</guid>
      <description>Preface Dieser Post enthält das Skript sowie die Aufgaben inklusive Lösungen meines Tutoriums “Einstieg in die Programmiersprache R” auf der 63. Jahrestagung der GMDS e.V. in Osnabrück am 6.9.2018. Das Skript mit den Aufgaben ohne Lösungen sind in der Datei workbook-rstats-gmds18-aufgaben.Rmd auf Github verfügbar.
Installation In diesem Kurs werden wir mit R und RStudio als Programmierumgebung (IDE) arbeiten. Beide Programme stehen kostenlos zur Verfügung.
Zunächst muss die Programmiersprache R installiert werden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join by rows</title>
      <link>/post/join-by-rows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/join-by-rows/</guid>
      <description>In a recent project I find myself often in the situation to deal with similar but not equal datasets. I am working with the German Hospital Registers for the years since 2005 and there is a dataset for each year.
Some of them share the same information stored in columns and I had to combine them in a single dataframe.
library(tidyverse)  ## ── Attaching packages ─────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.3.0 ── ## ✓ ggplot2 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import ordered SPSS factors into R</title>
      <link>/post/import-ordered-spss-factors-into-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/import-ordered-spss-factors-into-r/</guid>
      <description>SPSS Factor Variables Recently I have to work with data stored in SPSS files, most variables stored as ordered factor variables. Since I work with R, I have to import them. On the one hand, fortunatly, there is the haven package, which makes importing SPSS files an easy taks. On the other hand, unfortunatly, ordered factors are imported as integer values which are not associated with the corresponding factor label.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-02-upload-a-resource-to-a-fhir-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-02-upload-a-resource-to-a-fhir-server/</guid>
      <description>Upload a Resource to a FHIR Server       code{white-space: pre;} pre:not([class]) { background-color: white; }  if (window.hljs) { hljs.configure({languages: []}); hljs.initHighlightingOnLoad(); if (document.readyState &amp;&amp; document.readyState === &#34;complete&#34;) { window.setTimeout(function() { hljs.initHighlighting(); }, 0); } }  h1 { font-size: 34px; } h1.title { font-size: 38px; } h2 { font-size: 30px; } h3 { font-size: 24px; } h4 { font-size: 18px; } h5 { font-size: 16px; } h6 { font-size: 12px; } .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>