<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rstat on Science, Physiotherapy and Stats</title>
    <link>/tags/rstat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rstat on Science, Physiotherapy and Stats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jnshsrs&#34;&gt;Jens Hüsers&lt;/a&gt; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rstat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Logistic Regression Coefficients - Odds Ratios</title>
      <link>/post/interpreting-logistic-regression-coefficients-odds-ratios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/interpreting-logistic-regression-coefficients-odds-ratios/</guid>
      <description>Logistic Regression The Logisitc Regression is a generalized linear model, which models the relationship between a dichotomous dependent outcome variable \(y\) and a set of independent response variables \(X\).
However, to get meaningful predictions on the binary outcome variable, the linear combination of regression coefficients models transformed \(y\) values. The transformations is done via the Logit, which basically is the natural logarithm of the odds, also called Logit: \(log(\frac{p(x)}{1 - p(x)})\), where \(p(x)\) is the probability that \(y=\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koeffizienten des Bass-Models</title>
      <link>/post/estimating-the-bass-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/estimating-the-bass-model/</guid>
      <description>Untersuchung von Innovationen Vor dem Hintergrund immer schneller verlaufender Innovationszyklen und der zunehmenden Digitalisierung sind Modelle die versuchen Innovationsmechanismen zu erklären von großem Interesse. Obwohl die Innovationsforschung, die sich mit diesem Thema befasst, heutzutage einen großen Stellenwert einnummt, befassten sich Forscher um 1960 mit der Thematik. Insbesondere Rogers und Bass befassten sich der Erklärung und Modellierung von Innovationen. Bass gelang es als Erster ein mathematisches Model zur Erklärung von Innovationen und der Produktentwicklung zu erstellen, die ursprünglich von Rogers in seiner “Diffusion of Innovation Theory” aufgestellt wurden.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>