<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logistic Regression on Science, Physiotherapy and Stats</title>
    <link>/tags/logistic-regression/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Logistic Regression on Science, Physiotherapy and Stats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jnshsrs&#34;&gt;Jens Hüsers&lt;/a&gt; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/logistic-regression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Prediction for FHIR</title>
      <link>/post/risk-prediction-for-fhir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/risk-prediction-for-fhir/</guid>
      <description>Risk Prediction Based on clinical observations and classifications, clinical risk prediction models suppport clinicians to detect risk patients in an early stage of an amputation. Those patients may have a high likelihood of developing severe short or long term complications, such as heart attack or lower limb amputations.
Lower limb amputations are a feared complication with patients with an diabetic foot ulcer (DFU). In a recent effort, I developed a clincal prediction tool that estimates the patient’s risk of a lower-leg amputation, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Logistic Regression Coefficients - Odds Ratios</title>
      <link>/post/interpreting-logistic-regression-coefficients-odds-ratios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/interpreting-logistic-regression-coefficients-odds-ratios/</guid>
      <description>Logistic Regression The Logisitc Regression is a generalized linear model, which models the relationship between a dichotomous dependent outcome variable \(y\) and a set of independent response variables \(X\).
However, to get meaningful predictions on the binary outcome variable, the linear combination of regression coefficients models transformed \(y\) values. The transformations is done via the Logit, which basically is the natural logarithm of the odds, also called Logit: \(log(\frac{p(x)}{1 - p(x)})\), where \(p(x)\) is the probability that \(y=\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Cost Function of Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>/post/exploring-the-cost-function-of-logistic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/exploring-the-cost-function-of-logistic-regression/</guid>
      <description>This post is about exploring the cost function and its connection to the logistic regression function.
knitr::opts_chunk$set(echo = TRUE, warning=F, message=FALSE, fig.align=&amp;#39;center&amp;#39;) library(tidyverse) library(plotly) library(latex2exp) I want to get a deeper understanding of the connection between the logistic regresssion and its cost function. Therefore I created a function in R and conducted a grid approximation with this function. The results are presented below.
The logistic regression can be applied to data where the dependent variable is coded binary where the referent class is coded as a 1 and as 0 otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>